Home Address:

Telephone:

138 Whalley Road Wilpshire BB1 9LJ 07864 937530

Email: jameshodgson@live.co.uk

Curriculum Vitae: James Hodgson

Personal Profile

I am an extremely hard working, dedicated and reliable person who aims to achieve the best of his abilities. I consider myself to be honest and a caring person that collaborates well with other staff. Whilst I only have over a year's worth of commercial experience, I have spent over 7 years learning computer science. The work I have done has provided me with confidence, time management, and communication skills to excel in the computing industry. This demonstrates that I work hard, am trustworthy, and am dependable.

Skills Summary

For my age, I have many years of work experience, as I have always been driven by my work ethic and willingness to learn. In each role, I have quickly established myself as a valuable member of the team and have always worked to the best of my abilities and tried to learn as much as I could from every other team member, regardless of their level within the team.

I have gained easily transferable skills and experience, such as working to deadlines, and I work well under pressure. I work well as part of a team and consider myself to have effective communication skills. I have devoted my time to helping customers whenever I can, as they have always been my priority. These skills have helped me become the person I am today, and I now love to be challenged and strive to improve in all areas.

My interest in databases and SQL comes from my final year of university when I was asked to pick a focus for a project. This made me realise that databases are what I want to specialise in. I gained an understanding of MySQL and querying using SQL, as well as some Ubuntu Linux file server administration during my second year and chose Big Data as a topic for my project in my final year for which I developed using Java, MySQL, and PHP. The Java program ingested enormous amounts of raw data into the database which would then utilise trigger and procedures/functions to transform raw into usable data which was visualised via a URL.

I have always had a keen interest in gaming and game development. Over the last few years, I have been working on creating my own game using Unity with C# Scripts or Unreal Engine. I have made a lot of progress with the added bonus of becoming familiar with new languages and techniques through self-taught learning. I have found myself to be better with the code rather than model creation. My interest has pushed me to research and learn on multiplayer mechanics to build my game.

Technical Skills Summary

Personal/Workplace	University	A-level/High School
C#, TypeScript, Java, SQL, C++, Python Visual Studio, Unity, Unreal Engine, Git	Java, SQL, C#, Kotlin, Swift MySQL, Visual Studio, PHPStorm, Git, Android SDK, XCode	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Visual Basic BlueJ, Visual Basic, Greenfoot

Home Address:

Telephone:

138 Whalley Road Wilpshire BB1 9LJ 07864 937530

jameshodgson@live.co.uk

Education

BSc (Hons) Degree	A-level	GCSE
University of Salford Salford	St. Mary's RC College Blackburn	St. Augustine's RC High School Billington
Software Engineering	Computer Science ICT Business	Computer Science ICT Maths Additional Science Science Religious Education Geography English Language English Literature

Employment History

Salmesbury Hall, Salmesbury Role: Gardening/Ground Maintenance

Jun 2015 to Jul 2015

Duties: Delivering high quality maintenance/cleaning/gardening duties. Responsible for time management and ensuring jobs completed in time and to the required standard. I often excelled at this, as it was my first ever job and I was keen to impress. Due to this, I was often trusted to work unsupervised and trained using power tools not normally given to trainees.

The Bonny Inn, Salmesbury Role: Kitchen Porter, Waiter, Chef Aug 2016 to Oct 2018

Duties: I worked part-time in my local bar/restaurant whilst studying for my A-levels and full-time during the holidays. Initially I started this role in the kitchen as a porter, but quickly became trusted with more responsible duties such as food preparation because of my work ethic and willingness to learn all I could off the more experienced members of the team. I was encouraged to complete further in-house training doing waiting-on and some of the more difficult chef duties as time went by.

KFC, Barrow-Brook, Clitheroe

Role: Cook, Burger Station, Team Member

Sept 2019 to Aug 2022

Duties: Skills attained in the fast-food industry include; teamwork and management, multi-tasking and handling the fast-paced environments during rush periods, while keeping under control of all the pressure that came with it. I was able to expand on my customer interactions giving me the ability to handle stressful types of customers and allowing the customer to leave happily with the intention to always return.

I G T, Manchester Sept 2022 to ONGOING

Role: Software Engineer, Game Deliver Engineer

Duties: Write and test code, as and where needed as well as deploying maintainable and saleable code. Working in an agile sprint environment. Use of continuous integration and automated testing tools. Analysing user/client requirements and creating software to these requirements. Creating technical documentation.

Home Address:

138 Whalley Road Wilpshire BB1 9LJ **07864 937530**

Telephone: 07864 937530 Email: jameshodgson@live.co.uk

Maintaining software by monitoring. Simultaneously working on multiple games and issues. Training new colleagues.

References are available upon request

Interests and Hobbies

My interests include spending time with family and friends, listening to music and anything around computer programming.

I enjoy going to the cinema and music festivals and have a wide social group of friends.

I am interested in a career using my skills gained from commercial work experience and whilst studying for a Computer Science degree and completing my computer science GCSE and A-Level.

This has encouraged me to learn further computer languages and associated skills, including Arduino and Raspberry Pi development, and other programs during my spare time.

I have learnt the theory of many skills and techniques over the years studying and years in the working industry which would make me an excellent employee at your firm.